<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hash>
  <name>Bryan JJ Buckley</name>
  <goes-by type="array">
    <goes-by>JJ</goes-by>
    <goes-by>Bryan</goes-by>
  </goes-by>
  <tagline>Full-stack architect and coder</tagline>
  <headline>Looking for an interesting senior software-development position in a forward-thinking Berlin team using either NodeJS or Ruby on Rails.
</headline>
  <date-of-birth type="date">1978-10-24</date-of-birth>
  <email>jjbuckley@gmail.com</email>
  <phone>+49 176 49805866</phone>
  <nationality>Irish</nationality>
  <spoken-languages type="array">
    <spoken-language>English</spoken-language>
    <spoken-language>German</spoken-language>
    <spoken-language>Irish</spoken-language>
  </spoken-languages>
  <computer-languages type="array">
    <computer-language>Ruby</computer-language>
    <computer-language>CoffeeScript</computer-language>
    <computer-language>SASS</computer-language>
    <computer-language>HAML</computer-language>
    <computer-language>Javascript</computer-language>
    <computer-language>HTML</computer-language>
    <computer-language>CSS</computer-language>
    <computer-language>Python</computer-language>
    <computer-language>C</computer-language>
    <computer-language>Lisp</computer-language>
    <computer-language>Ada</computer-language>
    <computer-language>Lua</computer-language>
    <computer-language>C++</computer-language>
    <computer-language>SQL</computer-language>
  </computer-languages>
  <education type="array">
    <education>
      <qualification>BSc in Software Development and Computer Networks</qualification>
      <institution>CIT (Cork Institute of Technology)</institution>
    </education>
    <education>
      <qualification>CCNA (Cisco Certified Network Associate)</qualification>
      <institution>Cisco Networking Academy</institution>
    </education>
  </education>
  <experience type="array">
    <experience>
      <company>Dialogic</company>
      <from>2001</from>
      <to>2007</to>
      <position type="array">
        <position>Intern</position>
        <position>Software Developer</position>
        <position>Senior Software Engineer</position>
      </position>
      <overview>Dialogic (formerly Eicon Networks) are a global manufacturer of ISDN and DSL
hardware. After doing my work experience there as part of the BSc in
Software Development and Computer Networks, I was hired as a software engineer
for the embedded team.  There I worked primarily on protocol stacks for the
various firmwares (always in C). After some time, I moved onto developing
Windows drivers in C++. I discovered first Python and then Ruby whilst looking
for a solution to improve the build system for a newly acquired line of ISDN
modems and their driver packages. I later had the opportunity to write an early
Rails application which generates certificates for enabling driver features in
Eicon's entire telephony range. Thus encouraged, I decided to work on Rails
full-time.
</overview>
      <website>http://www.eiconworks.com</website>
      <id>eicon</id>
    </experience>
    <experience>
      <company>Travel IQ</company>
      <position type="array">
        <position>Senior Software Developer</position>
        <position>Architect</position>
      </position>
      <title>Travel IQ</title>
      <from>2007</from>
      <to>2009</to>
      <overview>Travel IQ was my first experience with a start-up, and it brought me to
Berlin. In 2006, after a telephone interview with the CTO, I was asked to come
to Berlin to meet the team of the fledgeling startup. I moved to Friedrichshain
in February 2007, and worked with Mathias and 4 part-time students to get the
app online for August 1st. After the launch, as senior developer/architect in an
expanding team, we set about re-writing the platform for Rails 2. In October
2008, version 2 was live, and in 2009, the company was aquired by Check24.
Mission accomplished, I left to travel.
</overview>
      <website>http://travel-iq.de</website>
      <id>tiq</id>
    </experience>
    <experience>
      <company>eBay</company>
      <from>2010</from>
      <to>2016</to>
      <position type="array">
        <position>IT Consultant</position>
        <position>Software Solutions Vendor</position>
      </position>
      <overview>In between travels, I've done some project work for eBay GmbH in Dreilinden.
I've whipped together a gem for using the eBay Trading API, and have built a
couple of Rails apps (one in Rails 2.3, and a more recent one Rails 3.2) which
are used for ranking signed-up users by their eBay trading data. The apps are
used internally by eBay to encourage customer engagement, and to push particular
verticals as needed. Other work includes a HTML5 photo-gallery (my first
introduction to CarrierWave), and a mobile front-end to the eBay Open
Global Competition app. As this is likely to continue, I spend some spare time
improving the eBay Open JSON API, and the open-source eBayR gem.
</overview>
      <website>http://ebay.com</website>
      <links type="array">
        <link>http://deutschland-index.com</link>
        <link>http://pm.bjjbuckley.com</link>
        <link>http://github.com/jjbuckley/ebayr</link>
      </links>
      <id>ebay</id>
    </experience>
    <experience>
      <company>SAP</company>
      <position type="array">
        <position>Software Solutions Vendor</position>
      </position>
      <from>2014</from>
      <to>2014</to>
      <overview>I was contracted by SAP to build an internal application, to manage their
security division's penetration tests every year. The app is mostly a
straightforward PostgreSQL backed RoR application, with incrementally more
detailed views for increasing levels of user responsibility, with
facilities to import data from Excel spreadsheets, and to generate PDF
reports. The app is continuously deployed in a docker container upon SAP's
internal PaaS system.
</overview>
      <website>http://sap.com</website>
      <id>sap</id>
    </experience>
    <experience>
      <company>DaWanda</company>
      <position type="array">
        <position>Software Consultant</position>
      </position>
      <from>2012</from>
      <to>2014</to>
      <overview>For DaWanda, I was the senior consultant on several of their projects, the
largest and most challenging of which were the rearchitcture of their
backend system (to an elastic, zero-downtime distributed VS cluster), and
the overhaul of their UI to a mobile-first, responsive layout for all
user-facing pages. I returned in 2014 to provide a Sinatra replacement for
their core legacy Rails app for their API services. In between were
several short projects, including improving their image-uploading
services, remodelling some of their MySQL database, and designing and
coding miscellaneous APIs and gems for their consumption.
</overview>
      <website>http://dawanda.com</website>
      <id>dawanda</id>
    </experience>
    <experience>
      <company>TrainMySelf</company>
      <position type="array">
        <position>CTO</position>
      </position>
      <from>2011</from>
      <to>2016</to>
      <overview>TrainMySelf GmbH is a company founded in 2011 by three guys from South Tyrol
and me (as CTO and lead - sometimes only - developer). The idea was to
produce an iPhone and Android app that delivers customized training plans to
marathon runners. Over the last year, we've hired a couple of additional
developers part-time and graphic designers, and it's grown to more of an
app-platform - with an administration interface to allow customization of
the mobile apps, and a delivery system for PhoneGap applications, all
powered by a JSON API which generates the training plans (in three
languages). TrainMySelf is due to be in beta in early June, at which point I
will be ready to devote the bulk of my energy to another exciting project.
</overview>
      <website>http://trainmyself.com</website>
      <links type="array">
        <link>http://blog.trainmyself.com</link>
      </links>
      <id>tms</id>
    </experience>
  </experience>
  <hobbies type="array">
    <hobby>Guitar playing</hobby>
    <hobby>Travelling</hobby>
    <hobby>Karate</hobby>
    <hobby>Football (soccer, rugby or GAA)</hobby>
    <hobby>Learning new things</hobby>
  </hobbies>
  <links type="array">
    <link>
      <name>GitHub Profile</name>
      <href>http://github.com/jjbuckley</href>
      <id>github</id>
    </link>
    <link>
      <name>Blog (when I blog)</name>
      <href>http://blog.bjjb.org</href>
      <id>tumblr</id>
    </link>
    <link>
      <name>Google+</name>
      <href>https://plus.google.com/115358926435312925527</href>
      <id>google</id>
    </link>
    <link>
      <name>Twitter feed</name>
      <href>http://twitter.com/#!/bjjbuckley</href>
      <id>twitter</id>
    </link>
  </links>
  <other-formats type="array">
    <other-format>yml</other-format>
    <other-format>txt</other-format>
    <other-format>json</other-format>
    <other-format>xml</other-format>
    <other-format>html</other-format>
  </other-formats>
</hash>
